<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>python - Tag - MagMax&#39;s blog</title>
        <link>https://magmax.org/en/tags/python/</link>
        <description>python - Tag - MagMax&#39;s blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magmax.org/en/tags/python/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Distributed Python: Celery</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/python-distribuido-celery/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/python-distribuido-celery/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Nowadays, SOA architectures is in fashion. These architectures use little and very specific services, so they interact each other.
In this post I&rsquo;ll show how to use Celery in order to create a SOA architecture.
  About Celery Celery is not a communication system, because it uses RabbitMQ, Redis, etc. as communication system. The same applies to argue it is not a message queue system. Neither it is a protocol, because it uses AMQP.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Why Python rocks</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/why-python-rocks/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/why-python-rocks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[After writting the article Why Java rocks, I have no other option than writting why Python rocks.
Before starting, I might advise you that Python is my favourite language. And this is like search your best friends defects.
  Python Rocks Dynamic typing Opposite to people&rsquo;s opinion, Python is strongly typed. But it is dynamically typed also. You cannot modify the type of a variable, but you can reuse the same variable to point to&hellip; another thing.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Python: Assignments with default values</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/python-asignaciones/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/python-asignaciones/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Some time ago, Manolowar showed me the operator [&ldquo;Elvis] from Groovy .
  This operator, written like: ?: is called in this way because it looks like an emoticon with toupee, just like Elvis Presley. It can be used like in C or Java (separated) or all together. When it is all together, it means something like: &ldquo;If value is false, assign me it, and if not, assign me this other one&rdquo;.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
