<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - MagMax&#39;s blog</title>
        <link>https://magmax.org/en/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | MagMax&#39;s blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magmax.org/en/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>ArgoCD with Kind</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/argocd/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/argocd/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post will document how to run an ArgoCD instance locally, using Kind to create the Kubernetes cluster. In addition, I will use cert-manager to create a self-signed certificate to serve it with HTTPS.
  Creating the cluster with kind First of all, is to have a Kubernetes cluster. You will require to have kind available in your path (maybe downloading to your ~/bin or ~/.local/bin makes the trick). This is the configuration file I used:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Is Code Coverage Irrelevant?</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/is-code-coverage-irrelevant/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/is-code-coverage-irrelevant/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[After reading the article &ldquo;Is Code Coverage Irrelevant?&rdquo; by Ron Jeffries I feel the necessity to accept the challenge and tell what I really think about code coverage.
I&rsquo;ve being thinking for some time about writting this article&hellip; So this is the best moment, I think.
  What does the coverage means? Let&rsquo;s start with this twit:
 Two projects, one has 95% code coverage with tests, one has 45%.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Distributed Python: Celery</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/python-distribuido-celery/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/python-distribuido-celery/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Nowadays, SOA architectures is in fashion. These architectures use little and very specific services, so they interact each other.
In this post I&rsquo;ll show how to use Celery in order to create a SOA architecture.
  About Celery Celery is not a communication system, because it uses RabbitMQ, Redis, etc. as communication system. The same applies to argue it is not a message queue system. Neither it is a protocol, because it uses AMQP.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>What is an Engineer?</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/que-es-ingeniero/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/que-es-ingeniero/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In this article I will talk about what Engineering means to me.
I&rsquo;d like to ask any reader that, before reading this article, use a couple of minutes to answer the question: &ldquo;What does &lsquo;to be an Engineer&rsquo; mean?&quot;. After this small exercise, I suggest to write a short answer down in a piece of paper.
After doing that, you can read the article. If it likes you or not, compare my answer with yours.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Gashlycode Tinies</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/gashlycode-tinies/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/gashlycode-tinies/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I&rsquo;m following the Software Security course at Coursera.
In this course, they explain how an adversary can take advantage of code defects and how to defend from them. I&rsquo;ve looking for some like this for long time.
At the end of one of the videos there is a kind of poetry I liked. But I didn&rsquo;t found it in Internet. So I&rsquo;ve copied it here. It gathers all kind of code defects we should avoid because an adversary can try to use them.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Why Python rocks</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/why-python-rocks/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/why-python-rocks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[After writting the article Why Java rocks, I have no other option than writting why Python rocks.
Before starting, I might advise you that Python is my favourite language. And this is like search your best friends defects.
  Python Rocks Dynamic typing Opposite to people&rsquo;s opinion, Python is strongly typed. But it is dynamically typed also. You cannot modify the type of a variable, but you can reuse the same variable to point to&hellip; another thing.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Why Java Rocks</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/why-java-rocks/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/why-java-rocks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Some days ago I browsed a Kinisoftware slideshow and he said that &ldquo;Java rules&rdquo;. He couldn&rsquo;t explain why Java rules at the end, so I decided to do it in his place.
But at the end I will explain why Java does not rule.
I hope that Kinisoftware can read this and criticate it with all his soul. Kini: This is for you!
  Java does rule Static typing The first thing you realize about Java is its static typing.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Constructors as simple as you can</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/constructores-simples/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/constructores-simples/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This week I realized about the difference between an ugly constructor and a pretty one. It is curious how easy doing it well is and how cheap it is, so I am going to share my point with you, waiting your comments.
Since I began to work, I have done lots of ugly things, so do not face me up if you find something mine done in a different way :D The real goal is to improve yourself day after day!]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Do not comment. Assert it!</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/asegura/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/asegura/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Today I have discovered lots of things about this great unknown assert.
It happens that I had a very strong debugging tool too close from myself and I hadn&rsquo;t used it.
Trying to fix this problem, I write this article, but I am not going to write anything that is not already written at Java Assert Documentation or Python Documentation.
  The more basic First step is to know how to use it.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>XML vs JSON (en)</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/xml-vs-json/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/xml-vs-json/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Lately I am seeing lots of comparatives between JSON and XML. I do not want to be less than them, so I investigated a little to enter in this kind of comparatives.
Sadly, I realized that they are not comparable. To compare XML with JSON is just like compare an OpenOffice document with a text file. They are completely different things.
A JSON file is a set of grouped data. Nothing more.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
