<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>debaday - Tag - MagMax&#39;s blog</title>
        <link>https://magmax.org/en/tags/debaday/</link>
        <description>debaday - Tag - MagMax&#39;s blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magmax.org/en/tags/debaday/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>EasyTag: a graphical interface to managing your music files&#39; tags</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/easytag/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/easytag/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Please, if you have not done it, read the Debaday article. Thank you.
This article of debaday site, by Dominique Cimafranca, were posted at https://debaday.debian.net/2008/09/14/mythtv-a-personal-tv-recorder/ on 25/08/2008.
  EasyTag is a graphical utility to edit the descriptive [ID3 lastmod: 2021-01-28 tags] for your music files. One will think primarily of MP3 files, but it also does other formats, such as Ogg, FLAC, MP4/AAC, MusePack, Monkey&rsquo;s Audio files and WavPack files (APE tag).]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Mythtv: A personal TV recorder</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/mythtv/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/mythtv/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Please, if you have not done it, read the Debaday article. Thank you.
This article of debaday site, by Karl Erlandson, were posted at https://debaday.debian.net/2008/09/14/mythtv-a-personal-tv-recorder/ on 14/09/2008.
  No one likes to sit at home and wait for their favorite show to come on anymore and many have turned to buying hardware to record them for later viewing. Popular solutions to this problem include the expensive and proprietary TiVo and cable/satellite boxes with built-in TV recorders.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Remind: a text based agenda and todolist manager</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/remind/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/remind/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Please, if you have not done it, read the Debaday article. Thank you.
This article of debaday site, by Olivier Schwander, were posted at https://debaday.debian.net/2008/11/16/remind-a-text-based-agenda-and-todolist-manager/ on 16/11/2008.
  There are lots of different tools for managing your time: Mozilla has a standalone solution: Sunbird and another one based on Thunderbird: Lighting, KDE has Korganizer and Gnome has the young gnome-agenda and the very popular Evolution, and we must not forget the most famous web based tool: Google Calendar.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Tellico: collection manager for books, bideos, music, and a whole lot more</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/tellico/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/tellico/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Please, if you have not done it, read the Debaday article. Thank you.
This article of debaday site, by Dean Serenevy, were posted at https://debaday.debian.net/2009/01/04/tellico-collection-manager-for-books-videos-music-and-a-whole-lot-more/ on 04/01/2009.
  You&rsquo;ve heard of book and movie collection organizers, but Robby Stephenson&rsquo;s tellico is a general purpose collection manager. This application can be used to store information about arbitrary collections of whatever tickles your fancy. Tellico is available from the tellico package in Debian since Sarge and in Ubuntu since Dapper.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>bash-completion: the greatest things since bash completion</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/bash-completion/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/bash-completion/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Please, if you have not done it, read the Debaday article. Thank you.
This article of debaday site, by &ldquo;Andre Masella&rdquo;, were posted at https://debaday.debian.net/2009/03/01/bash-completion-the-greatest-things-since-bash-completion on 01/03/2009.
  Pressing the tab key in bash to auto-complete a file name is one of the most time saving tricks especially when dealing with very long file names. Unfortunately, file name completion is not always the right behavior. Take Subversion for example. The first argument to svn is the sub-command to use.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>vnstat: a console-based network traffic monitor</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/vnstat/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/vnstat/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Please, if you have not done it, read the Debaday article. Thank you.
This article of debaday site, by &ldquo;András Horváth&rdquo;:https://log69.com/index_en.html, were posted at https://debaday.debian.net/2009/02/08/vnstat-a-console-based-network-traffic-monitor/ on 08/02/2009.
  There are many command-line utilities in the Unix / Linux world that collect network traffic statistics for a chosen interface.
vnstat is different because statistics are collected permanently. It keeps the data in files so traffic monitoring is resumed at reboot. vnstat can be useful in situations when you need to know the exact amount of traffic that goes through the interface for a period longer than the computer is on.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Debaday</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/debaday/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/debaday/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Once upon a time, there were a web page very interesting titled Debian Package of the Day.
All of their articles were lost. I&rsquo;m trying to recover as much as I can. They may be incomplete.
Please, if you have any of them or you were the author of it, tell me.
Thank you a lot.
Really the idea began before of that. Here you can see the first post at Debaday, titled &ldquo;Hello, World&rdquo;, by &ldquo;lucas&rdquo;:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Fonty Python</title>
    <link>https://magmax.org/en/blog/debaday-fonty-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://magmax.org/en/blog/debaday-fonty-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Please, if you have not done it, read the Debaday article. Thank you.
This article of debaday site, by &ldquo;Donn Ingle&rdquo;, were posted at https://debaday.debian.net/2009/02/22/fonty-python-manage-your-fonts/ on 22/02/2009.
Fonty Python is available from the fontypython package in both Debian and Ubuntu in Universe. Fonty is a wxPython app so will work in any desktop environment. It also has a command-line interface which avoids the gui.
  What the font? As a graphic designer, one is called-upon to create artwork for many things.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
