<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code retreat on MagMax&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/tags/code-retreat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code retreat on MagMax&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/en/tags/code-retreat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code Retreat Global Day: Retrospective</title>
      <link>http://example.org/en/blog/coderetreat-global-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/en/blog/coderetreat-global-day/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been waiting for it for a long time. Lots of people join together all
around the world to improve their skills as Developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the chance of attending the Madrid meeting. It was carried on by Enrique
Comba. There I found a lot of people that I met first time in another Code
Retreat, a year ago. I met new people too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/images/gdcr.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Global Day of Code Retreat&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first thought was that I must not to be there. I already have been practising
the &amp;lsquo;kata&amp;rsquo; and I already knew the result. But some time later, realize that the
solution doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. It is the people who matters. It is more important to
speak with them, to think with them. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matters if you get the answer.
The real important thing is that you met another people, and each of them allows
you to see the same problem from another perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt a lot. I realize I was trying to solve the problem by my own, without
my mate. In another team, we didn&amp;rsquo;t write a lot of code, but we could think
about the mistery of life. In another one, the same happened, but about the
abstraction of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a very short day, and it was a very important opportunity to meet some
people who does mind about our job, about computer programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I feel lucky for having been there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all, organization teams, mates, friends. Thank you for your comments
or your thoughts, for your your words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
